Jeff Gold Collection ARC.0037
Library and Archives
- Series V: Posters, 1964-2001, undated
  - Subseries 2: Multiple Artists, 1966-1994, undated
    - Blue Cheer with Country Joe and the Fish, Avalon Ballroom, New Year's Eve, undated (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-4, Object 12)
    - The Blues Project with Sons of Adam and Quicksilver Messenger Service, Avalon Ballroom, 1966 May 13-14 (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-2, Object 12)
    - Bola Sete, Country Joe and the Fish, Buffalo Springfield, 1966 November 11-13 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-7, Object 9)
      A2004.54.210
    - Tim Buckley, the Velvet Underground, and All Men Joy, 1968 July 19-21 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-6, Object 17)
      A2004.54.194
    - Buffalo Springfield, and the Collectors, 1967 December 21-23 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-7, Object 5)
      A2004.54.206
    - Butterfield Blues Band, Jefferson Airplane, and Big Mama Mae Thornton, 1966 October 14-15 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-5, Object 7, Drawer-folder FF.3.5-3, Object 12)
      A2004.54.163
    - Butthole Surfers with Stone Temple Pilots, 1995 (Drawer-folder FF.3.1-1, Object 5)
      A2001.93.68
    - Captain Beefheart and His Magic Band, Chocolate Watch Band, and The Great Pumpkin, 1967 Oct. 28-30 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-5, Object 12)
      A2004.54.168
    - The Chambers Brothers
      - With Quicksilver Messenger Service, and Sandy Bull, 1967 April 7-9 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-5, Object 8)
        A2004.54.164
      - With the Velvet Underground, and Dr. John, 1968 (Drawer-folder FF.3.1-1, Object 6)
        A2001.93.30
        Shrine Exposition Hall, Los Angeles
    - The Charlatans, Triple AAA, and Frumious Bandersnatch, undated (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-5, Object 9)
      A2004.54.165
      Western Front Dance Academy, San Francisco
    - Otis Clay and Ann Peebles, undated (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-1, Object 3)
    - Creedence Clearwater Revival, Northern California State Youth Choir, Bangor Flying Circus, 1969 May 22-25 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-7, Object 4)
      A2004.54.205
      Fillmore (5/22, 5/25) and Winterland (5/23-24), San Francisco
    - Daily Flash
      - With Country Joe and the Fish, Avalon Ballroom, 1966 October 21-22 (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-3, Object 18)
      - With Quicksilver Messenger Service and Country Joe and the Fish, Avalon Ballroom, 1966 November 18-19 (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-3, Object 19)
      - With Rising Sons, Avalon Ballroom, 1966 May 6-7 (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-3, Object 20)
    - Dance of the Five Moons, 1967 March 3-4 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-6, Object 20)
      A2004.54.197
      Country Joe and the Fish, The Sparrow, and Kaleidoscope
    - Dinosaurs with Dan Hicks, Old Waldorf, Dec. 10, undated (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-3, Object 4)
    - The Doors, Chuck Berry, Big Brother and the Holding Company, Quicksilver Messenger Service, Jefferson Airplane, 1967 December 26-31 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-2, Object 9)
      A2002.82.24
    - The Drifters and Solomon Burke, undated (Object Museum storage)
      A2005.105.110
      Atlantic Records promo, includes song listing
    - Firehose
      - With Trotsky Icepick, Dos, Radwaste, 1987 September 12 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-6, Object 5)
        A2004.54.177
        Music Machine, Santa Monica
      - With Universal Congress of, Trotsky Icepick, 1987 August 22 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-6, Object 4)
        A2004.54.176
        Anti-club on Melrose, Los Angeles
      - With Universal Congress of, Trotsky Icepick, 1987 August 29 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-7, Object 10)
        A2004.54.211
        Al's Bar, Los Angeles
    - Flatt & Scruggs with Jack Elliott and Sons of Champlin, Avalon Ballroom, Sept. 27-29, undated (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-4, Object 11)
    - Fugazi with Fluf, Glasshouse, March 7 (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-4, Object 2)
    - Grandmaster Flash, Ronnie Dyson at Club Prince, 1983 October 29 (Object Museum storage)
      A2005.105.19
    - Grass Roots with Daily Flash and Sopwith Camel, Avalon Ballroom, 1966 July 1-3 (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-3, Object 28)
    - Grateful Dead
      - With James Cotton Blues Band, and Lothar and the Hand People, 1966 November 18-20 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-7, Object 8)
        A2004.54.209
      - With Sopwith Camel, 1966 August 19-20 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-5, Object 14)
        A2004.54.170
      - With Lightning Hopkins, 1966 October 21-22 (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-3, Object 27)
    - Bill Haley with the Drifters and Flaming Groovies, Avalon Ballroom, August 16-18, undated (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-4, Object 8)
    - Jimi Hendrix and Soft Machine with Electric Flag and Blue Cheer, Shrine Auditorium, 1968 February 10 (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-2, Object 8)
    - Hurricane Festival, 1998 (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-1, Object 9)
    - Millie Jackson and RL Griffin, undated (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-1, Object 4)
    - Jane's Addiction, the Pixies, Primus, undated (Object Museum storage)
      A2005.105.27
      Seattle Center Arena
    - Jefferson Airplane
      - With the Marbles, Great Society, and the Charlatans, undated (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-1, Object 14)
        Longshoreman's Hall, San Francisco
      - With P.H. Phactor Jug Band, and Andrew Staples, etc., 1966 September 2-3 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-5, Object 11)
        A2004.54.167
        Other artists
        Grateful Dead, Quicksilver Messange Service, Country Joe and the Fish: 9/4/66; Martha and the Vandellas, Johnny Talbot, De Thangs: 9/5/66.
      - With Muddy Waters, 1966 September 23-24, 1966 September 30, October 1 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-7, Object 6)
        A2004.54.207
        Also advertises Butterfield Blues Band show at the Fillmore, Sept. 25 and Oct. 1, 1966
    - Junior Wells, Avalon Ballroom, May 3-4 with Canned Heat, May 5 with Crome Syrcus, 1968 May 3-5 (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-3, Object 21)
    - Kaleidoscope with Mother Earth, Avalon Ballroom, 1968 June 21-23 (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-3, Object 13)
    - King Kong Memorial Dance, 1966 February 26 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-6, Object 1)
      A2004.54.173
      The Grass Roots, Big Brother and the Holding Company, and Quicksilver Messenger Service
    - KMPX 1st Birthday Benefit concert, Winterland, 1968 April 3 (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-3, Object 29)
    - Lollapalooza, King County Fairgrounds, WA, undated (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-5, Object 2)
      A2005.105.30
      Jane's Addiction, Siouxsie and the Banshees, Violent Femmes, Ice-T, Fishbone, Henry Rollins Band
    - Lollapalooza promo, 1994 (Drawer-folder FF.3.1-1, Object 14)
      A2001.93.58
    - Love, Everpresent Fullness, 1966 August 5-6 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-6, Object 19)
      A2004.54.196
    - Mariposa Folk Festival, 1965 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-1, Object 7)
    - Max's Easter Rock Festival, circa 1970s (Object Museum storage)
      A2005.105.55
      Max's Kansas City, New York
    - MC5, the Charles Moore Ensemble, 1967 June 30 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-1, Object 8)
      The See Theater, Detroit
    - Miller Blues Band, Lee Michaels, and Congress of Wonders, 1967 January 21 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-6, Object 18)
      A2004.54.195
    - Miller Blues Band, Mother Earth, and Bukka White, 1967 September 1-3 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-6, Object 3)
      A2004.54.175
    - Moby Grape
      - With Love, and Lee Michaels, 1966 December 2-4 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-7, Object 7)
        A2004.54.208
      - With the Sparrow, and the Charlatans, 1967 January 13-14 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-6, Object 7)
        A2004.54.181
      - With Traffic, the Lemon Pipers, and Spirit, 1968 March 22-23 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-6, Object 16)
        A2004.54.193
    - Mother Earth with Kaleidoscope, Avalon Ballroom, 1968 November 8-10 (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-3, Object 14, Object 15)
    - Mother Love Bone
      - With Alice in Chaines at OZ, Seattle, undated (Object Museum storage)
        A2005.105.23
      - With Alice in Chains at The Central Tavern, Seattle, undated (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-5, Object 1)
        A2005.105.28
      - With Shotgun Mama, Talks Cheap, undated (Object Museum storage)
        A2005.105.47
    - The Move, Leo Kottke, Goose Creek Symphony, and Brinsley Schwarz promo, 1971 March (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-1, Object 1-2)
    - Nirvana, Screaming Jay Hawkins, Fitz of Depression, undated (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-5, Object 3)
      A2005.105.45
    - Porno for Pyros and Cornershop, Fillmore, 1996 June 18 (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-4, Object 3)
    - Richard Pryor with Etta James, Shubert Theatre, Los Angeles, October 14-19 (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-2, Object 11)
    - Quicksilver Messenger Service, The Charlatans, and Congress of Wonders, 1967 December 15-17 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-5, Object 15)
      A2004.54.171
    - Radiohead and David Gray, Fillmore, 1996 March 27 (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-4, Object 13)
    - The Ramones with Dickies, Fillmore, 1988 July 11 (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-1, Object 11)
    - The Ramones, and Maze, 1975 February 25 (Object Museum storage)
      A2005.105.5
      Mt. St. Mary, Nashua, NH (first show by the Ramones outside of New York City)
    - Otis Rush and his Chicago Blues Band, the Grateful Dead, and Canned Heat, 1967 February 24-26 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-5, Object 10)
      A2004.54.166
    - San Francisco International Pop Festival, Alameda Fairgrounds, Oct. 26-27, undated (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-2, Object 7)
    - Santana
      - With Sea Train, and Yusef Lateef, 1969 September 4-7 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-6, Object 22)
        A2004.54.200
      - With Collectors, Melanie, 1969 September 13-16 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-7, Object 1)
        A2004.54.201
    - Second Annual Tribal Stomp, 1967 February 17-18 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-5, Object 5)
      A2004.54.192
      Feature artists
      Big Brother and the Holding Company, Quicksilver Messenger Service
    - Sing Out for Sight benefit, undated (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-2, Object 1-3)
    - Soundgarden, Screaming Trees, Tad, undated (Object Museum storage)
      A2005.105.25
      Moore Theatre, Seattle
    - Sphinx Dance, Avalon Ballroom, 1967 February 10-11 (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-3, Object 10)
    - St. Valentine's Day Dance with Quicksilver Messenger Service, Dino, and Blue Cheer, Fillmore, undated (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-2, Object 13)
    - Stamping Ground, undated (Object Museum storage)
      A2005.105.61
      Pink Floyd, Santana, Jefferson Airplane, Canned Heat, T. Rex, Al Stewart, Country Joe and the Fish, Flock, The Byrds, It's a Beautiful Day, and Dr. John
    - A Star is Born filming announcement, undated (Drawer-folder FF.3.3-5, Object 13)
    - Steve Miller Band with Howling Wolf, Avalon Ballroom, July 12-14 (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-3, Object 22)
    - Rod Stewart, and Deborah Harry (double-sided), undated (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-1, Object 4)
    - Sun Ra and his Arkestra, The Urbations, Ronald Shannon and the Decoding Society, Oliver Lake & Jump Up, Leon Thomas, and Wendall Harrison, 1983 September 17 (Object Museum storage)
      Saint Andrew's Hall, Detroit
      A2005.105.26
    - T.S.O.L. with Red Cross; Cramps, at the Country Club, April 18, April 30 (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-3, Object 17)
    - Traffic, with H.P. Lovecraft, Mother Earth, and Blue Cheer, 1968 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-5, Object 16)
      Fillmore (3/14/68) and the Winterland (3/15-16/68)
      A2004.54.140
    - Velvet Underground, Chambers Brothers, Dr. John, Pinnacle and Salvation, 1968 May 24-25 (Object Museum storage)
      A2005.105.20
      signed artist proof
    - Whiskey-a-go-go, December 15-18 (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-4, Object 5)
    - Zachariah, 1970 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-4, Object 3)
      A2002.82.190
  - Subseries 3: Subjects
    - Destroy All Music!, undated (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-4, Object 6)
      Dangerhouse record label punk compilation (Los Angeles)
    - Dogtown and Z-Boys [film], undated (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-2, Object 8)
    - Earth Girls Are Easy [film], 1989 (Drawer-folder FF.3.2-2, Object 15)
    - Genesis [film], 1969-1972 (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-3, Object 5-9)
    - Pirate Radio, by S. Clay Wilson, 2006 (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-4, Object 16)
    - Rock Mass at the Calvary Presbyterian Church, San Francisco, 1967 June 2 (Drawer-folder FF.3.3-4, Object 4)
    - That Was Rock [film], 1984 (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-1, Object 10)
    - San Francisco Oracle cover, Vol. 1 no. 9, 1967 (Drawer-folder FF.3.5-1, Object 9)
    - Shelly's Manne-Hole, wall calendar, 1964-1965 (Drawer-folder FF.3.3-1, Object 6)
      A2002.82.230
- Series VI: 16 Magazine Files, 1964-1987, undated
  The 16 Magazine Files series contains files kept by 16 Magazine over the years 1964-1987. The files document popular artists featured in the magazine, primarily in the form of photographs, some of which are marked on front and/or back with cropping instructions. The exception is two files of fan mail, which highlight other artists who were popular with the magazine's readers, such as the Bay City Rollers.
  - Allman Brothers Band, 1974-1981 (Box SM1, Folder 1)
  - The Beatles, undated (Box SM1, Folder 2, Folder 3)
  - Fan Mail, 1977-1988 (Box SM1, Folder 4-5)
  - Herman's Hermits (Object Museum storage)
    A2004.54.233
  - Jagger, Chris, 1973, undated (Box SM1, Folder 6)
  - The Kinks, 1967; 1981-1987 (Box SM1, Folder 7-8)
  - The Monkees (Object Museum storage)
    A2004.54.232
  - The Rolling Stones, 1964-1992 (Box SM1, Folder 9-13)
    A2004.54.234
  - Smith, Patti, 1973-1978 (Box SM1, Folder 14)
  - T. Rex (and Marc Bolan), undated (Box SM1, Folder 15)
    A2004.54.231
  - The Who, 1975-1985 (Box SM1, Folder 16-19)
- Series VII: Audiovisual Materials [RESTRICTED], 1966-2001, undated
  The condition of some of these materials has not yet been determined for playback purposes. Some of the audiovisual materials in the collection are on defunct media formats and, therefore, are RESTRICTED. Access copies of these materials may have to be created prior to use. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit to ensure access to these materials is available.
  Series VII: Audiovisual Materials contains both audio recordings and video tapes that date from the years 1967-2001. These materials are arranged by audio or video format, and then alphabetically by artist name or event title.
  - Subseries 1: Audio [RESTRICTED], 1966-2001, undated
    The condition of some of these materials has not yet been determined for playback purposes. Some of the audiovisual materials in the series are on defunct media formats and, therefore, are RESTRICTED. Access copies of these materials may have to be created prior to use. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit to ensure access to these materials is available.
    The audio recordings found here are primarily either audiocassettes or 1/4-inch audio tapes. The content of the former is mostly artists' appearances on radio shows, such as Howard Stern or other morning shows from the Los Angeles area. The reels contain studio work, such as demo recordings.
    - Boone, Pat (audiocassette), 1996 July 18 (Box AV1, Cassette 1)
    - Bowie, David (1/4-inch reel), undated (Box AV5, Reel 1)
    - The Byrds (1/4-inch reel), 1977 (Box AV5, Reel 2)
    - Checker, Chubby (1/4-inch reel), 1980 December 8 (Box AV2, Reel 4)
    - Coolidge, Rita (1/4-inch reel), undated (Box AV2, Reel 2)
    - Dylan, Bob (1/4-inch reels), circa 1966, 1974 (Box AV5, Reel 3-4)
    - Elliott, Cass (1/4-inch reel), undated (Box AV5, Reel 5)
    - Erickson, Roky (1/4-inch reel), undated (Box AV5, Reel 10)
    - Fairport Convention (1/4-inch reels), 1973, 1979 (Box AV5, Reel 6-9)
    - Fogerty, John (audiocassettes), 1997 (Box AV1, Cassette 2-5)
    - Golden Earring (1/4-inch reels), undated (Box AV5, Reel 10-11)
    - Goo Goo Dolls (audiocassettes), 1999-2001 (Box AV1, Cassette 6-10)
      audio cassettes (4), television appearances and interviews on VHS (5), Betacam SP (1), and U-Matic (1) formats.
    - Hagar, Sammy (audiocassettes), 1997 (Box AV1, Cassette 11-14)
    - Hendrix, Jimi (1/4-inch reels), undated (Box AV5, Reel 12-13)
    - International Artists (1/4-inch reels), undated (Box AV5, Reel 14-15)
    - Jackson, Joe (audiocassettes), 1988 (Box AV2, Cassette 1-2)
    - Jagger, Mick (1/4-inch reel), undated (Box AV2, Reel 5)
    - Jan and Dean (1/4-inch reel), undated (Box AV5, Reel 16)
    - John, Elton (1/4-inch reel), undated (Box AV5, Reel 17)
    - Lofgren, Nils (1/4-inch reel), 1977 (Box AV5, Reel 18)
    - Los Lobos (audiocassette), 1996 May 16 (Box AV1, Cassette 15)
    - Nico (with John Cale; 1/4-inch reel) (Box AV5, Reel 19)
    - Nugent, Ted (audiocassette), undated (Box AV1, Cassette 16)
    - Parker, Graham (1/4-inch reels), 1978 (Box AV6, Reel 1-2)
    - Petty, Tom (1/4-inch reel), 1978 (Box AV6, Reel 3)
    - Playboy Awards (1/4-inch reel), undated (Box AV2, Reel 3)
    - Rolling Stone magazine promotional minidisc (Sony minidisc), 1994 (Box AV2, Disk 1)
    - The Rolling Stones (audiocassette, 1/4-inch reel), undated (Box AV1, Cassette 24, Box AV2, Reel 6)
    - Roth, David Lee (audiocassette), 1996 (Box AV1, Cassette 17)
    - Seatrain (1/4-inch reel), undated (Box AV2, Reel 1)
    - Silver Apples (1/4-inch reels), 1969 (Box AV6, Reel 4-7)
    - Spirit (1/4-inch reels), 1967, undated (Box AV6, Reel 8-15)
    - Spooky Tooth (1/4-inch reels), 1979 (Box AV5, Reel 9, Box AV6, Reel 16)
    - Springsteen, Bruce (audiocassettes), undated (Box AV1, Cassette 18-20)
    - Steel Mill (1/4-inch reels), 1970 (Box AV6, Reel 17, Box AV5, Reel 3)
    - Stern, Howard (audiocassette), 1997 (Box AV1, Cassette 21)
    - Stevens, Cat (1/4-inch reel), 1979 (Box AV6, Reel 18)
    - Turner, Ike and Tina (1/4-inch reel), 1979 (Box AV6, Reel 19)
    - Van Halen (audiocassettes), 1996, undated (Box AV1, Cassette 22-23)
    - The Who (1/4-inch reels), undated (Box AV7, Reel 1-2)
    - Various artists (1/4-inch reels), 1979 (Box AV7, Reel 3-7)
  - Subseries 2: Video [RESTRICTED], 1971-2001, undated
    The condition of these materials has not yet been determined for playback purposes. Access copies of these materials may have to be created prior to use. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit to ensure access to these materials is available.
    The videos found here are primarily VHS, and contain either television appearances or promotional content, including in-store events and concerts. There is also 8mm and 16mm film and H-8.
    - Bumbershoot: the Seattle Arts Festival promo tape (VHS videocassette), undated (Box AV4, Cassette 14)
    - The Concert for the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame (VHS videocassette), 1996 September 6 (Box AV3, Cassette 23)
    - Crosby, Stills, Nash and Young (VHS videocassette), 2000 (Box AV3, Cassette 16-17)
    - Goo Goo Dolls (VHS videocassette), 1999-2001 (Box AV3, Cassette 11-15)
    - Grand Funk Railroad (16mm film reel), undated (Box AV4, Reel 17)
    - Hendrix, Jimi (VHS videocassette), 1995, undated (Box AV4, Cassette 1-4)
    - lang, k.d. (VHS videocassette), 1995-2001 (Box AV3, Cassette 1-10)
    - Lennon, John (VHS videocassette), 1971, 1975 (Box AV3, Cassette 22)
    - Los Lobos (VHS videotape), 1996 May 16 (Box AV3, Cassette 18-19)
    - R.E.M. (VHS videotape), 2001 (Box AV3, Cassette 24-27)
    - The Rolling Stones (8mm film reel, 16mm film reel), undated (Box AV4, Reel 15-16)
    - Screaming Lord Sutch (8mm film reel, DVD transfer), undated (Box AV2, Disk 2, Reel 7)
      8mm sound musical, with transfer copy on DVD
    - Simon, Paul (VHS videocassette), 2000 (Box AV3, Cassette 20)
    - Van Halen (VHS videocassette), 1998-1999, undated (Box AV4, Cassette 5-13)
    - Williams Brothers (Hi-8), undated (Box AV3, Cassette 28)
    - Young, Neil (VHS videocassette), 1994 October 4 (Box AV3, Cassette 21)